hello everyone
and today I want to bring your attention to this particular kind of universal automation
I first discovered this setup during a multiplayer speedrun which highlighted its downsides
but it is probably good in normal runs
and I also figure out on usage which makes it even better than CIBs in some particular situations
but now enough talking
let's start building it one piece at a time
to start we need to split the main network which is the one with blue cables
from the working network which is the one with red cables
here I'm using advanced stocking hatches
I can think of ways of not using those
but the next game version is probably going to change AE2 fluid mechanics
so for this quick video I'm keeping it this way
and the main way this system works is through toggle buses
if you don't know how those work
basically what I talk about does is that
with the redstone, it will connect or disconnect
this one is a normal one which connects with the redstone
this one is an inverted one which connects when there is no redstone
can probably see it better isn't this
when the lever is in this state this cable goes there
when I pull it
you should update
okay it goes there
and you can already see the main downside of this thing
the main downside is that it takes a little bit for the network to update every time you pull the lever
it should be instantaneous
but from experience it's not fast enough
so if you use this
you have to consider that it's got to be a little bit slow
but by doing bigger batches
it doesn't have that issue
I just make a huge batch
so that the redstone toggling happens once every two minutes
but of course we are not going to use a lever
but some kind of automation
in this case we are going to use the level emitters
yeah the idea is that
once there is something to craft
the level emitter will disconnect the next segment of the automation
and it will connect the crafting slice
by the way for the rest of this video
I'm going to try to improvise
because I find it slightly harder to read a script, synchronize everything etc etc
if I improvise I get lost a little bit more
but if I script it feels too artificial to me
so I'm going to try this video this way
tell me later what you think about it maybe
anyways the main concepts here is that
the main line will connect to only one of those outputs of all time
we're going to have multiple later
and one good part thing of this setup is that you can just copy paste those line later
but the main idea is that
this redstone will toggle this
so it either connects to this
or to the next part
this is the main thing
now another trick I want to show
is that if you're naming things
you can do something easy to type like ASD
and then instead of looking for things
you can just find everything you need
there are pins you can use too
but I don't like how pins use up all of the space there
yeah probably was better with pins (?)
but I like it more to have it
also if you rename things
those are named things won't be used by AE2 craft
so if I craft more of those
it will not take my quartz fiber
if I craft more of those (maybe delete this line?)
if I craft those renamed
those won't be used into other crafting like (eye of harmony?) part
keeping those stocked in endgame is a little bit hard
because they keep getting used to craft other stuff
if you name things you always have some there
anyways let's use phosphoric acid as an example
which has a bunch of different ingredients
we'll see about catalyst slightly later
catalyst means stuff like circuits
we will see about circuits later
now I'm using dual interfaces here
but
you can use a normal interface
and then you can put the export bus with wild card
on a packet decoder on an input hatch with a pump
if you can't use this one because you don't have it yet
but as I said
I think fluids are going to be reworking the next GTNH version
so this may works differently in the next version
like working with (solid n' fluid?) this is something kind of normal
which I'm not going to dive into details for this video
anyways main network interface we put in a pattern
this one will drop fluid and solids into this sub network here
now this one
you could just put a drive in there
link it there and it will just work
yes I could use a red cable
that connect all of this to this blue cable
it could work
I used to use it this way
but I figured out if we do some extra steps
it actually works better
so this would be the purple network
of course we're going to have our driver
let's try to make it
you can build probably in a nicer way than I do
I'm not good at making things that look nice
so it is what it is
okay those are (delete?)
yeah having everything renamed to ASD may not be bad (?)
this one has to be renamed later
that's really easy to find everything like that
than the pins (?)
okay I really discussed that
so we have this main sub network there
we get the stuff stocked up
this network will drop this stuff into this sub network
which will go there
also let's not forget the blocking card mode and the blocking mode
to avoid messing up ingredients
okay then this one will go there
I'm going to show later okay
this one is only solid
so we also need a fluid level emitter
we have to set those to 1
when levels are above
okay when there is more than one item right
so we toggle on
it will disconnect these lines and connect this one
same goes with this one
okay
maybe later I'm going to try some trickery to make it work differently
I'm still working this
I'm finding out better ways of doing it
actually I'm still getting this one to work better
now this network (gots from?) its power
we could use a quartz fiber
but I'm using I'm in a game
I'm currently using Twist Space
this is not all GTNH stuff
there is nothing twisted
I mean this one is expensive
you can just use quartz fiber
not much stuff nothing special
anyways okay here if you work out
now let's get a terminal
I'm not working in my main network
I'm working in this sub network
this one is my real main net
doing this sub network for an experiment
now here should be able to see let's actually show only
okay we can make for for do we need (?) right
oh wait they also need a CPU
crafting storage
okay now we have a crafting storage
so we start crafting something
we can see this stuff goes in there
both of those toggled on
this one got disconnected
and now this one is connected
now of course we have to connect this stuff to the machine
so to do that
we make another subnet interfacing
we can probably just go with this
okay do I have enough space there
okay the red one is the one that must be able to see the other one
so let's try to make it a little bit nicer
that does not look nicer
but whatever
so
wait I'm lost this one
let's have those on extract only
and nothing should happen
but rather have those on extract only
okay this way
the red network should now see the contents in there
see
okay oxygen, water, phosphorus dust
now there is no circuit
but we can fix that easily
now one way of adding circuit
is to simply put a circuit in this cell
by doing that
that would work
let's show
okay that one would directly work
okay
but the issue is that if we would go with that
okay I used a small wireless
because I didn't want this one to instantly work
but apparently I put too much stuff
well you know it works that instantly done
now this don't empty it
but the issue is that as you can see
okay it did took a little bit to toggle off if you paid attention
（向上合并）
the issue is that we have one circuit in there
so there is always one item
but this one can easily be fixed by doing two items
and now this one is empty until we order more
and this one is empty
so this one is now disconnected
and it's connecting the next step
we order more we can see that
we order more, it goes in there, toggle's on, works
toggle's off, reconnects this one
okay
so this one could not really be a way of doing it
and then you simply copy paste this
you put different circuits in a every cell
but I personally liked it more
I liked it more if instead of doing it this way
I do a different thing which is
we basically do another subnet or with the catalyst
so if we do that
we keep this one on 1
we put a storage center with a chest
okay that is the other way of doing it
instead of that way
instead of keeping circuits inside the cell
you can keep the circuit in the chest
that way this one is always empty
you do it this way just by flying
you can see if it is green
it means it's empty
if there is something
you know it's not a catalyst
but it's actually something
that's one of the reasons why I want to do that
but the real reason why I want
basically a third subnet for inputs
is the real advantage of this setup
which I'm going to show later on
so okay this one basically works now
let's try again because I changed it again
okay
so turns on
toggles, this one true okay
that really works
it did its thing and now it's already reset
okay so the next stage is expanding this
then I'm going to show another thing
okay
and now I'm going to just use the matter manipulator
to copy paste this slice and make more of it
now there is one small issue
I found with this version
there's (no more?) issue with level emitters
of course it's not finding a couple of things
but it's fine
when you copy paste level emitters
it does not copy paste the setting
so you have to manually fix this
I didn't check
AE2 was getting a little bit rework in next GTNH version
it's still in not even beta right now
it's experimented it's being worked on
so didn't even check what they are doing
now you can put a different circuit in each one of those
whenever something goes in there
it will cut out everything else and craft this one
so this setup will always prioritize this line there
once this one is empty
it will switch to this one
and so on until he finds one with something inside
this is a nice (addon?)
it has its pros and cons compared to other automation systems
I haven't found another video explaining this particular way of doing it
anyways the main advantage of this thing is that specifically with the DTPF
（向上合并）
you can also add other stuff in the catalyst network
now in the other setup I had a chance with circuits
here I'm using
I'm using this thing which is super cool
this one is to prevent things from constantly being drained from the main net
it buffers a bit of materials so it doesn't constantly drain main net
I'm putting there those catalysts
those are used as circuits
I'm using this one as the chest previously
this stuff is never used
and as you can see I'm putting there
in this chest with things that are theoretically not consumed also the DTPF fuel
that is because
one annoying thing with DTPFs is that
once you get convergence
if you want to do patterns with convergence there are a few issues
I have various kind of issues in the past with using DTPF pattern for convergence
okay one thing which is not the real issue
is that you have to calculate the amount of DTPF fuel used by each pattern
and that can be a little bit annoying
if you use this setup you don't have to
but the thing is that
as far as I understand
I haven't done that in too much
I only tried once didn't work well
if you calculate how much fuel the DTPF is going to take
and then in the future you decide to overclock it
you basically have to redo the pattern with the fuel which is annoying
if you do it this way
the fuel is not inside the pattern
so it simply takes it from there
and yeah that is the main advantage
I figured out of this system
I really think this is great for convergence on DTPFs
okay if you don't know
you can paint hatches to set priorities
black painted hatches will always have priority over red
which has priority over green then brown then blue etc etc
that way
if you have a passive high energy recipe like space time that does not use catalyst
if it ever runs out of catalyst
in this thing
it will simply switch to the other recipe
it just works without converging
because it doesn't have fuel in the blue hatch
it doesn't have fuel in blue hatch
so it doesn't converge
the thing is that even if there is fuel in there
it will not converge something
it will not converse something in a blue hatch
if the fuel is in a black hatch
that's the good thing I figure out that can make this thing work
so if you go this way
if you want to overclock these in the future
you don't have to redo the pattern with your amount of fuel
also I had issues when I did this with CIBs
it will mess up things
this way it seems to work really nicely
also I think this setup probably can be made in other modpacks
anyways yeah I think that's it
I will have made this video like 10 times shorter probably if I edited it better
I wanted to try this different editing style
tell me what you think about it
main downside of this system is that
the redstone takes a little bit to update
many people say redstone doesn't cause much lag
but I don't know
I'm not a fan of things that use redstone
also had bad experiences with toggle buses in my net in the past
having a toggle bus which keeps toggling on and off
especially in a big network
can be an issue I think
but it should have been fixed
so just saying that avoid doing quick toggle buses which is in the main network mostly
if it is in such a small network
it's probably not a big deal
but I don't know
I'm paranoid
yeah I think that's it
also with this editing style I probably forgot like half of the things I was supposed to say
tell me what do you think about this kind of editing
bye bye
大家好
今天我想给大家介绍一种特殊的通用自动化方案
我最开始是在多人速通里发现这套方案的，这也暴露了它的缺点
不过在正常流程里，它大概还是挺好用的
我还摸索出了一些用法，在某些特定场景下甚至比样板总成好用
但闲话就先说到这儿
我们一步步来搭它
首先要把主网络，也就是蓝线
和工作网络分开，工作网络用的是红线
这里我用的是进阶存储输入总线
其实也能不用这些
但下一个版本大概率会改 AE2 的流体机制
所以这条视频里我就先按这个做法来
这个系统的核心是ME触发总线
如果你还不知道它的效果
大致就是：
它会随着红石信号接通或断开
这个是正常的，有红石信号时导通
这个是反相的，没有红石信号时导通
这样应该更容易看明白一点吧？
当拉杆保持这个状态时，这条线会接到那边
我拉一下拉杆
更新
好，现在它接过去了
你现在应该已经能看出它最大的缺点了
最大的问题是，每次拉动拉杆后，网络都要花一点时间才能更新
理论上应该是瞬间完成的
但按我的经验来看，它还是不够快
所以如果你要用这个方案
就得考虑到它会稍微慢一点
不过如果把批量做大一点
这个问题就不明显了
我通常会直接做一大批
这样红石切换大概两分钟才会触发一次
当然，我们不会真的靠拉杆来控制
而是会用某种自动化方式
这里我们使用物品发信器
思路是：
一旦有东西要合成
物品发信器就会断开自动化流程的下一段
同时接通要合成那一段
顺带一提，视频的后半部分
我会即兴来讲（苦死翻译了）
因为我发现照着脚本念、还要同步各种操作，会有点难受
当然，即兴的话我也会更容易讲着讲着跑偏
但如果完全照稿子来，又会让我觉得太僵硬
所以这期我就试试这种方式
之后告诉我你们觉得怎么样
总之，主要思路是
主线一次只会连到其中一个输出
后面我们会做出多个分支
这个装置有个好处，就是之后可以直接复制粘贴整条线路
但重点还是在于
红石会切换主线的连接
所以它要么连到这边
要么连到下一段
这就是最关键的部分
接下来我想再演示一个小技巧
如果你给东西重命名了
可以起个很好输入的名字，比如 ASD
这样你就不用到处翻找
直接搜名字就能找到需要的东西
你也可以用 pin
但我不喜欢 pin 把第一行全占掉
对，可能用 pin 会更好一点（？）
但我还是更喜欢现在这种方式
另外，如果你给东西重命名了
这些被重命名的东西就不会被 AE2 合成直接拿去用了
所以如果我再做更多这种东西
它就不会把我已命名的石英纤维用掉
如果我再合成更多这类东西（删这句？）
如果我合成这些重命名过的东西
这些也不会被别的配方拿去用，比如用于（鸿蒙之眼？）部件
后期把这些东西一直留着有点难
因为它们总会被拿去做别的东西
但只要你给它们改名，就总能留下一些库存
总之，我们拿磷酸来举例
它需要好几种不同的材料
催化剂我们稍后再说
催化剂指的就是编程电路这类东西
编程电路我们后面也会讲
这里我用的是二合一接口
不过
你也可以用普通接口
然后把带通配符的输出总线放到ME流体封包解码器上，再接一个带泵的输入仓
（重新分句）
如果你现在还没有这些部件，也可以先不用这种做法
不过就像我前面说的
我觉得下一个 GTNH 版本大概会重做流体
所以下个版本的设置可能不同
像这种同时处理固体和流体的做法，本来也算常见
这部分我就不在这个视频里细讲了
总之，主网接口这里放一个样板
这个会把液体和物品都送进这个子网里
然后这个地方
你可以直接放一个ME驱动器
接到那边就能正常工作了
对，我也可以直接用红线
把这些全都连到这条蓝线那边
这样也能工作
我以前就是这么用的
但我后来发现，如果多加几步
效果反而更好
所以就有了紫色网络
当然也少不了驱动器
我们来试着搭一下
你们大概能搭得比我好看得多
我本来就不太会做美观的东西
所以就这样吧
好，这些就是（删这句？）
对，把所有东西都重命名成 ASD 可能也不错
这个之后还得再改名
像这样找东西真的很方便
比 pin 还顺手
好吧，这个我已经说过了
这是主要的子网络
材料都会送进这里
这个网络会把这些东西送进这个子网络
然后它们就会传到那边
别忘了用阻挡卡，把阻挡模式打开
这样才不会把材料搞乱
好，这个放这里
我后面再给大家看，行吧
这个只处理物品
所以我们还需要一个流体发信器
这些都要设成 1
当数量高于
也就是超过 1 个物品的时候，对吧
这样一切换
它就会断开前面的线，接上这条线
这个也是同理
好
也许之后我会试试别的技巧，看看能不能换种工作方式
我还在继续琢磨这个
我在找更好的做法
实际上我还在继续把它调得更顺手
现在给这个网络的供电
可以直接用石英纤维
不过我现在的游戏版本
我现在加了TST
这玩意儿也不完全是 GTNH 里的东西
没什么特别扭的地方
我是说这个挺贵的
其实直接用石英纤维就行
材料不多，也没什么特别的
总之，差不多到这里就行了
现在我们拿个终端出来
我不是在主网络里操作
我是在这个子网络里操作
那边才是我真正的主网
这个子网络只是拿来做实验的
现在这里应该能看到，我们先打开只显示……
好，我们来做做看需要的东西
哦等等，还需要一个 CPU
合成存储元件
好，现在有合成存储元件了
那我们开始合成点东西
你可以看到材料进到里面了
这两个发信器都打开了
这个断开了
然后这个连上了
当然，我们还得把这部分接到机器上
要这么做的话
我们再做一个子网接口
先这样接应该就行
空间够吗？
红色这条必须能看到另一边那个
所以我们尽量把它摆得好看一点
嗯，看起来并没有更好看
不过无所谓
那就这样
等等，我有点绕晕了
把这些设成“仅提取”
这样就不该发生任何事
应该只会提取
好，这样的话
这样红色网络现在应该能看到里面内容了
看到没
好，氧气、水、磷粉
现在还缺编程电路
但这个很容易补上
加编程电路的一种方法是
直接在这个存储元件里放一个编程电路
这么做的话
机器就能正常工作
我演示一下
好，这种方式能直接工作
好
但问题是如果这么做
我这边用了个小的无线能源仓
因为我不想让它立刻做完
但显然我塞的东西太多了
所以你看，它几乎瞬间就做完了
现在存储单元没有被清空
但问题是，你也看到了
如果你刚才有注意，它要再花时间切回去
（向上合并）
问题在于这里还有一个编程电路
所以存储单元里面永远会有一个物品
不过这个很好修，改成要两个物品就行
现在在我们下更多单之前，这里会被视为空的
这个也是空的
所以这个就断开了
然后连到下一段输入
我们再下单就能看到
下更多单，物品进来、触发打开，机器工作
触发关闭后，又会重新连回这一条
好
这并不是唯一做法
你也可以直接把这套复制粘贴
然后在每个存储元件里放不同电路
但我个人更喜欢
不按这种方式来
我会用另一种方案
基本上就是再做一个子网来放催化剂
如果这么做
就把这个值设成 1
然后放一个带箱子的存储总线
这就是另一种做法
不是前面那种
与其把电路放在存储元件里
你可以把电路放在箱子里
这样存储单元就会一直是空的
用这种做法你飞过去时
看一眼是不是绿色
绿色就代表是空的
如果里面有东西
你就知道那不是催化剂
而是真的有材料
这也是我这么做的原因之一
但我真正想这么做的原因
是做一个第三输入子网
这才是这套配置真正的优势
我后面会演示
好，这套装置现在基本能用了
我们再试一次，因为i我刚又改了一点
好
现在它打开了
切换触发，这个状态是对的
确实能工作
它完成流程后已经重置了
下一步就是把多做几个这样的单元
然后我再演示另一件事
好
现在我直接用物质操纵者
把这一段复制粘贴，多做几组
不过这里有个小问题
我在这个版本里发现
物品发信器有个问题
当然现在有几样东西没识别到（？）
但没关系
复制粘贴物品发信器时
它的设置不会被一并复制
所以你得手动改这些设置
我还没去确认
下个 GTNH 版本里 AE2 会重做
现在连 beta 版都还没出
还在实验和开发阶段
所以我还没细看他们具体改了什么
现在你可以在每个单元里放不同的编程电路
只要有东西进来
它就会切掉其他线路，优先做这一条
所以这套会始终优先这一条线
一旦这条空了
它就会切到下一条
以此类推，直到找到有东西的一条
这算是个不错的（补充方案？）
跟其他自动化相比，它有自己的优缺点
我还没见过别的视频讲这种具体做法
总之，这套东西优势是最能体现在 DTPF 上
（向上合并）
你可以在催化剂网络里额外塞别的东西
前一种做法里我用的是电路
而这里我用的是
这个很酷的组件
它是为了防止材料持续从主网被抽走
会先缓冲一部分材料，避免一直抽主网
我把这些催化剂放在这里
它们是当作编程电路来用的
这里我用它来替代之前那个箱子
这里面的东西不会被直接消耗掉
你可以看到我放进去的内容
这个箱子里既有理论上不消耗的东西，也有 DTPF 燃料
这是因为
DTPF 有个很烦人的点
就是一旦它进入维度收敛
你要做带收敛的配方时会遇到一些问题
我以前做 DTPF 配方收敛时踩过不少坑
有一件事其实不算真正的问题
就是你得计算每个配方会消耗多少 DTPF 燃料
这会有点烦
如果用这套配置，你就不用算
但问题在于
据我理解
我没有特别深入地尝试这样做过
我只试过一次，效果不太好
如果你先把 DTPF 所需燃料都算进配方
之后你又决定去超频它
基本就得重算一遍配方的燃料，这很烦
如果用我这种做法
燃料不写进配方里
机器就会直接从那边取燃料
对，这就是主要优势
也是我在这套系统里发现的重点
我真的觉得它特别适合做 DTPF 收敛
如果你还不知道
你可以给仓室染色来设置优先级
黑色仓室总是优先于红色仓室
红色又优先于绿色，再是棕色，再是蓝色，依此类推
这样的话
如果你有一个被动高耗能配方，比如不吃催化剂的时空
当催化剂用完时
在这套系统里
它就会自动切到另一个配方
这样它会以非收敛方式运行
因为蓝色仓室里没有燃料
蓝色仓室没燃料（删这句或者上一句？）
所以就不会收敛
关键是就算系统里有燃料
它也不会在这里触发收敛
不会在蓝色仓室对应的配方收敛
前提是燃料在黑色仓室里
这是我发现能让这套稳定工作的关键点
所以如果你这样自动化
以后想给这些机器超频时
你不需要按燃料量去重做配方
另外我以前用样板总成做这个也遇到过问题
配方很容易串
而这套看起来稳定得多
另外我觉得这套配置在其他整合包里应该也能做
总之，差不多就这些
如果我剪得更好，这期视频大概能再短个十倍
我只是想试试这种不同的剪辑风格
你们可以告诉我感受
这套系统的主要缺点是
红石更新会有一点延迟
很多人都说红石不会带来太多卡顿
但我也不太确定
我个人不太喜欢红石驱动的东西
我以前在主网里用触发总线也有过糟糕经历
那种会不停开关的触发总线
尤其是在大网络里
我觉得可能会出问题
不过理论上现在应该修过了
所以只是建议，尽量别在主网络里做高速触发总线
如果是在这种小网络里
可能问题不大
但我也说不准
我就是有点太谨慎了
嗯，大概就这些
另外用这种剪法，我可能漏掉了一半本来想说的内容
告诉我你们对这种剪辑方式的看法
拜拜